Guide to the Joseph Urban Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series 1: Vienna, 1897-1911
  - Subseries I.5: Exhibits
    - Hagenbund Exhibition Hall, 1901-1902:
      - --Front elevation and ground plan, 29x18 cm. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - --Ceiling, 19x22 cm. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 4 magazine clippings (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Art show catalogs:
      - Watercolor club,1899 (Box B3, Folder 2)
      - Secession 14th exhibit (Box B3, Folder 3)
      - Vienna Art Show, 1908 (Box B3, Folder 4)
    - Hagenbund Exhibits:
      - 32 Hagenbund exhibit catalogs, 1902-1906 (Box B3, Folder 5-36)
      - 4 Hagenbund catalogs, 1905, 1908, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 23-26)
      - 1902 exhibit, Playroom, sig. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 56 photographs of exhibits (2 sets of 28) (Box 5, Folder 1 & 2)
      - 14 St. Louis World's Fair photograph and copies (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1905, 14 photographs of exhibit (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1905-06, exhibit #19, Wall elevation, 38x40 cm. (Box C2, Folder 1)
      - 1906, 2 plans for 20th Exhibit (Box C2, Folder 2)
      - 1906, 4 photographs of 20th Oct-Nov exhibit (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 15 photographs of exhibits, unidentified (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1908, 19 exhibit photographs (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1906 London announcement, 16x11 cm. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1910, elevation of Redlich exhibit room, 58x41 cm. (Box D1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries I.6: Unidentified
    - Playbooks, Moliere (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 17 watercolor drawings (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 22 drawings and plans (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 9 photographs (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 9 drawings (Box A1, Folder 9-10)
    - Clock elevation, 21x29 cm., sig. (Box B2, Folder 10)
    - 3 elevations (Box C2, Folder 3)
    - Vorraum elevations (Box D1, Folder 5)
    - Plans for home and office (Box 14-9-1, Folder A.4)
- Series II: Boston Opera, 1910-1914
  Joseph Urban was made artistic director of the Boston Opera Company beginning with the 1912-1913 season. The previous season, he had designed four operas for the Boston Opera while working in Vienna with Heinrich Lefler. This series contains files on all the productions from the repertory in chronological order. Each production is listed by title, opening date and production information. The production information is based on contemporary reviews taken from microfilm readings of the Boston Transcript and the Boston Herald. Those sets that Urban redesigned or retouched are so noted in parentheses after the title information. In addition to the drawings, plans, and photographs, the files contain production records--light plots, cast lists, set lists, line drops, etc
  - La Scala invoice for operas Mefistofele, Faust, Lakmé, Manon and Roméo et Juliette:
    - Costume Invoice September 1910, 4 p. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ground Plan, Mefistofele (Box 14-9-1, Folder A5)
  - Pelléas et Mélisande, January 10, 1912 (New)
    Opera in 5 acts by Claude Debussy, adapted from the play by Maurice Maeterlinck, conducted by André Caplet with Vanni Marcoux as Golaud, Georgette LeBlanc as Mélisande and Jean Riddez as Pelléas.
    - Maeterlinck playbook incl. Pelléas et Mélisande (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1 drawing of dungeon, pencil (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 10 technical drawings (Box C2, Folder 4)
    - 10 technical drawings (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 2 drawings of furniture, watercolor (Box C2, Folder 4)
    - Production notes, 25 p. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 7 photographs of sets (Box 5, Folder 8)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, March 21, 1925]
  - Hänsel und Gretel, January 27,1912 (New)
    Opera by Engelbert Humperdinck, libretto by Adelheid Wette, after a fairy tale by the Grimm Brothers, conducted by Wallace Goodrich with Bernice Fisher as Gretel, Jeska Swartz as Hänsel, Maria Claessens as the Witch, Otto Goritz as Peter and Florence De Courcy as the Sandman.
    - 6 drawings, watercolor & ink:
    - --5 details of shoes and head pieces (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - --Details of wigs and head pieces (Box B2, Folder 11)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 5, 1927]
  - Tristan und Isolde, February 12, 1912 (New)
    Opera in 3 acts by Richard Wagner, conducted by Felix Weingartner, with Johanna Gadski as Isolde, Jacques Urlus as Tristan, Pasquale Amato as Kurvenal and Edward Lankow as King Marke
    - Libretto (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Set notes in German (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Set drawing, watercolor and pencil:
    - --Act I: boat scene (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 2 elevations of Act I and II (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 2 technical drawings (Box D1, Folder 6)
    - Electrical plot (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 5 photographs of sets (Box 5, Folder 10)
      [See also Vienna, 1909-11; Theater, Interstate Opera 1916; Metropolitan Opera, November 20, 1920]
  - Werther, March 1, 1912
    Opera by Jules Massenet, conducted by André Caplet
    - Production notes, 3 p. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Germania, March 9, 1912
    Opera by Alberto Franchetti, conducted by Arnaldo Conti with Bernice Fisher as Jane, Ramon Blanchart as Crisogono, Madeleine D'Olige as Jebbel, Pasquale Amato as Carlo Worms, Carmen Melis as Ricke and Giovanni Zenatello as Loewe.
    - Production notes, 2 p. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Le Martyre de Sebastien, March 30, 1912
    Music by Claude Debussy, conducted by André Caplet with Evelyn Scotney and Jeska Swartz.
    - 2 set notes (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 2 set sketches (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Les Contes d'Hoffmann, November 25, 1912 (New)
    Opera by Jacques Offenbach, libretto & book by Jules Barbier, after a play by Barbier & Michel Carré based on the stories of the poet E.T.A. Hoffmann, conducted by André Caplet with Edmond Clément as Hoffmann, Vanni Marcoux as Lindorf, Coppélius, Dappertutto and Dr. Miracle, Elvira Leveroni as Niklausse, Bernice Fisher as Olympia and Louise Edvina as Antonia.
    - Libretto (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Clipping from German magazine (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 3 set sketches, Opéra Comique production (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Set notes, 31 p. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Production notes, 11 p. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 17 drawings, watercolor, pencil and ink:
    - --7 costume drawings (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - --2 costume drawings, Giulietta (Box B2, Folder 12 & 13)
    - --6 set details (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - --2 set details (Box B2, Folder 14)
    - 1/2 detail of elevation, photostat (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 5 ground plans (Box B2, Folder 14)
    - 6 photographs of costume drawings (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 26 photographs of sets (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Note to Deems Taylor, 1934, ts. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 13, 1924]
  - La Bohême, November 27,1912 (retouched)
    Opera by Giacomo Puccini, libretto by Signori Giocosa and Illica, adapted from a novel by Henri Murger, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Lucrezia Bori as Mimì, Léon Laffitte as Rodolfo, Giovanni Polese as Marcello and Fely Dereyne as Musetta.
    - 2 librettos (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1 p. from Met program, 1913-14 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 2 costume drawings, watercolor and pencil (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 3 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1 cast list from December 6 performance (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 5 production notes, 6 p. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 2 photographs of sets (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Madama Butterfly, November 29, 1912 (New)
    Opera by Giacomo Puccini, libretto by Giuseppe Giacosa & Luigi Illica, after a play by David Belasco, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Riccardo Martin as Pinkerton, Emmy Destinn as Cio-Cio-San and Giovanni Polese as Sharpless.
    - Libretto, German (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Set notes in German, 8 p. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Act II, watercolor (Box B2, Folder 15)
    - 5 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 2 ground plans (Box B2, Folder 16)
    - Production notes, 10 p. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 6 photographs of set (Box 6, Folder 4)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 24, 1922]
  - Il Trovatore, November 30, 1912
    Opera by Giuseppe Verdi, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Gertrude Rennyson as Leonora, Léon Laffitte as Manrico, Ramon Blanchart as Di Luna and Maria Claessens as Azucena.
    - Libretto (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Production notes, 21 p. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 4 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 3 ground plans (Box B4, Folder 1)
    - 1 set photograph of III.1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tosca, December 2, 1912 (retouched)
    Opera by Giacomo Puccini, book by V. Sardou, L. Illica and G. Giacosa, after Victorien Sardou's play La Tosca, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Mary Garden as Tosca, Vanni Marcoux as Scarpia, Charles Dalmorès as Cavaradossi, and Aristodemo Sillich as Angelotti.
    - Libretto in German (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 2 clippings from program (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Watercolor drawing of Act III: Castle Terrace (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Set notes, 8 p. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 2 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Production notes, 16 p. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 3 photographs of set (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Thaïs, December 7, 1912 (retouched)
    Opera by Jules Massenet, libretto by Louis Gallet, after a novel by Anatole France, conducted by André Caplet with Mary Garden as Thaïs, Vanni Marcoux as Athanael and Charles Dalmorés as Nicias.
    - Set notes, 7 p. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Production notes,18 p. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 2 photographs of set (Box 6, Folder 7)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, December 14, 1922]
  - Lucia di Lammermoor, December 14, 1912
    Opera by Gaetano Donizetti, conducted by Ralph Lyford with Evelyn Scotney as Lucia, Umberto Sacchetti as Edgardo, Rodolfo Fornari as Enrico and Ernesto Giaccone as Arturo.
    - Production notes, 20 p. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Photograph of set (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Louise, December 18,1912 (New)
    Opera by Gustave Charpentier, conducted by André Caplet with Louise Edvina as Louise, Edmond Clément as Julien, Maria Gay as La Mère and Vanni Marcoux as Le Père.
    - 2 references clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 3 set renderings, watercolor:
    - --Act I & IV: Garret (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - --Act II: At the foot of Montmartre (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - --Act III: Garden (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 2 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1 ground plan, Act II (Box 14-9-1, Folder A6)
    - Production notes, 12 p. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 5 photographs of set drawing and sets (Box 6, Folder 9)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, March 1, 1929]
  - La Traviata, December 21, 1912
    Opera by Giuseppe Verdi, based on the story by Alexandre Dumas La Dame Aux Camelias, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Evelyn Scotney as Violetta, Alfredo Ramella as Alfredo, Ramon Blanchart as Germont and Attilio Pulcini as Baron Douphol.
    - 3 ground plans (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Production notes, 11 p. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of set (Box 6, Folder 10)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 14, 1921]
  - Aïda, December 27, 1912 (Retouched)
    Opera by Giuseppe Verdi, libretto by Antonio Ghislanzoni, after a scenario by Auguste Mariette, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Giovanni Zenatello as Radames, Anafesto Rossi as Amonasro, Maria Gay as Amneris and Carmen Melis as Aïda.
    - 2 librettos (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Set notes in German, 4 p. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 4 ground plans (Box B4, Folder 2)
    - 3 costume sketches (Box B25, Folder 7)
    - Production notes, 19 p. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 3 photographs of sets (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Coppélia, December 28, 1912
    Ballet by Léo Delibes, conducted by Charles Strony with Dolores Galli as Swanilda. Attilio Pulcini as Burgomaster and Cronan as Frantz.
    - Ground plan (Box B4, Folder 3)
    - Production notes, 5 items (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 2 photographs of sets (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cavalleria Rusticana, December 30, 1912
    Opera by Pietro Mascagni, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Maria Gay as Santuzza, Umberto Sacchetti as Turiddu, Anafesto Rossi as Alfio.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Production notes, 3 p. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Photograph of set (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Curtain and Concerts, 1912-13
    - (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 2 ground plans, 1912 (Box B4, Folder 4)
    - 2 drawings of drapery ornament, watercolor, Feb 1913 (Box B4, Folder 5)
  - I Pagliacci, January 4, 1913
    Opera by Leoncavallo, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Edith Barnes as Nedda, Ramon Blanchart as Tonio, Giuseppe Gaudenzi as Canio and George Everett as Silvio.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Village, watercolor, sig. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ground plan (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 5 p. production notes (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Photograph of set (Box 7, Folder 5)
      [See also Theater, Interstate Opera Company 1916]
  - Carmen, January 15, 1913 (retouched)
    Opera by Georges Bizet, libretto by Henri Meilhac & Ludovic Halévy, after a novel by Prosper Mérimée, conducted by Charles Strony with Giovanni Zenatello as Don Jose, Maria Gay as Carmen and José Mardones as Escamillo.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Clipping of Met stage sets (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 8 ground plans (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 4 ground plans (Box B4, Folder 6)
    - 28 production notes (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 2 photographs of set (Box 7, Folder 6)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 22, 1923]]
  - I Gioielli della Madonna, January 17, 1913 (New)
    Opera by Ermanno Wolf-Ferrari, libretto by Carlo Zangarini & Enrico Golisciani, with Giovanni Zenatello as Gennaro, Maria Gay as Carmela, Louise Edvina as Maliella and Vanni Marcoux as Raffaele.
    - Synopsis in German, 24 p. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Article in German, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 3 prints of Charlottenburg sets by von Plessen (Box B4, Folder 7)
    - 3 renderings, watercolor:
    - --2 costume renderings, Madonna, 24x14 cm. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - --Procession scene, 17x31 cm. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 2 rough sketches (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 3 ground plans, Berlin opera house (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1 ground plan (Box B4, Folder 7)
    - 1 cast list (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 9 photographs of sets (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rigoletto, January 25, 1913
    Opera by Giuseppe Verdi, libretto by Francesco Maria Piave, after the play by Victor Hugo Le roi s'amuse, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Evelyn Scotney as Gilda, Michele Sampieri as Monterone, Rodolfo Fornari as Rigoletto and Alfredo Ramella as the Duke.
    - 1 cast list (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1 set of production notes, 17 p. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1 set photo (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Don Giovanni, February 7, 1913 (New)
    Opera by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, libretto by Lorenzo Da Ponte, conducted by Felix Weingartner with Vanni Marcoux as Don Giovanni, Adamo Didur as Leporello, John McCormack as Don Ottavio, Emmy Destinn as Donna Anna and Elizabet Amsden as Donna Elvira.
    - Cast list (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
    - --Act I: Garden scene, signed by Errol (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 3 ground plans (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 3 technical drawings (Box B4, Folder 8)
    - Production notes, 6 p. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 13 retouched photos of sets (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 22 photographs of sets and set drawings (Box 7, Folder 10)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera, November 29, 1929]
  - La Fanciulla del West, February 21, 1913
    Opera by Giacomo Puccini, libretto by Guelfo Civinini & Carlo Zangorini, based on the play by David Belasco The Girl of the Golden West, with Carmen Melis as Minnie, Giovanni Polese as Jack Rance and Giovanni Zenatello as Dick Johnson.
    - Ground plan (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - 3 ground plans (Box 14-9-1, Folder A7)
    - Production notes, 9 p. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - 2 photographs of set (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Djamileh, February 24, 1913 (New)
    American premiere of opera by Georges Bizet, libretto by Louis Gallet, after the story by Alfred de Musset Namouna, conducted by Felix Weingartner with Lucille Marcel as Djamileh, Léon Laffitte as Haroun and Ernesto Giaccone as Spendiano.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Set notes in German, 34 p. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 3 rough set sketches: (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
    - --wall elevation, 22x29 (22x23) cm., sig. (Box B4, Folder 9)
    - Production notes, 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 3 photographs of set (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Faust, February 26,1913 (redesigned costumes, retouched)
    Opera by Charles Gounod, libretto by Jules Barbier & Michel Carré, adapted from the dramatic poem by Goethe, conducted by Felix Weingartner with Giovanni Zenatello as Faust, Lucille Marcel as Marguerite and Vanni Marcoux as Méphistophélès.
    - 2 librettos (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 1 costume drawing, watercolor (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 4 ground plans (Box B4, Folder 10)
    - Production notes, 18 p. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 12 photographs of costume and set drawings (Box 7, Folder 13)
      [See also Vienna 1906-07 and Metropolitan Opera, 1917 and 1923]
  - La Forêt Bleue, March 8, 1913 (American premiere) (New)
    Opera by Louis Aubert, conducted by André Caplet with Fernand De Potter as Prince Charming, Jean Riddez as the Orge, Carmen Melis as the Princess, Jeska Swartz as Tom Thumb and Bernice Fisher as Little Red Riding -Hood.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Synopsis, 5 p. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Production notes, 9 p. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - 4 photographs of sets (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Samson et Dalila, March 12, 1913 (retouched)
    Opera by Camille Saint-Saëns, libretto by Ferdinand Lemaire, conducted by André Caplet with Maria Gay as Dalila, Giovanni Zenatello as Samson and Jean Riddez as the High Priest.
    - Libretto (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Postcard of set (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Set rendering, watercolor (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Production notes, 11 p. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 2 photographs of costume and set (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Il Segreto di Susanna, March 17,1913 (New)
    Opera by Ermanno Wolf-Ferrari, libretto by Max Kalbeck, adapted from a book by Enrico Golisciani, conducted by André Caplet with Antonio Scotti as Count Gil, Alice Nielsen as Countess Gil and Luigi Tavecchia as Sante.
    - Libretto (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1 p. of sample fabrics, costume (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Drawing of back wall, watercolor (Box B4, Folder 11)
    - 2 watercolor drawings, side wall and detail (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 10 plans and sketches (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 3 ground plans (Box D1, Folder 7)
    - Production notes, 8 p. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 6 photographs of set (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Martha, March 24, 1913
    Opera by Friedrich von Flotow, libretto W. Friedrich, after an idea by Jules-Henri Vernoy de Saint-Georges, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Alice Nielsen as Lady Harriet, Maria Gay as Nancy, Max Lipmann as Lionel and Edward Lankow as Plunkett.
    - 1 ground plan, Act III & V (Box D1, Folder 8)
    - 2 set notes and plan (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Production notes, 8 p. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Photograph of set
      [See also Metropolitan Opera December 14, 1923]
  - Monna Vanna, December 5, 1913 (New)
    Opera by Henri Février, based on a play by Maurice Maeterlinck, conducted by André Caplet with Vanni Marcoux as Guido, Mary Garden as Monna Vanna and Lucien Muratore as Prinzivalle.
    - Libretto, German (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Production notes, 31 p. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 3 working photographs (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 3 set renderings, watercolor on board:
    - --Act I: Interior (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - --Act II: Tent (painted photo) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - --Act III: Terrace (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 2 watercolor sketches with plan (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 2 detail drawings, watercolor, 1 sig. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-2, Folder 1)
    - 11 photographs of sets and scenes (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Il Barbiere di Siviglia (The Barber of Seville), December 13, 1913
    Opera by Gioachino Rossini, libretto by Cesare Sterbini, adapted from the play by Pierre-Augustin Beaumarchais, conducted by Arnaldo Schiavoni with Hazel Sanborn as Rosina, Rodolfo Fornari as Figaro, Luigi Tavecchia as Dr. Bartolo and Alfredo Ramella as Il Conte D'Almaviva.
    - 2 ground plans (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ground plan, Act I (Box B4, Folder 12)
    - Production notes, 6 p. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of Act II (Box 8, Folder 4)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera November 27, 1919]
  - Die Meistersinger Von Nürnberg, January 23, 1914 (New)
    Opera by Richard Wagner, conducted by André Caplet with Johanna Gadski as Eva, Robert Leonhardt as Beckmesser, Paolo Ludikar as Hans Sachs and Carl Jörn as Walther.
    - Reference material (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Reference material (Box 14-9-2, Folder 2)
    - 7 drawings, watercolor and pencil on board:
    - --Act I: Church, 19x26 cm. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - --Property elevations, 19x27 cm., sig. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - --Act II: Costumes, night scene, 18x26 cm., sig. (Box B4, Folder 13)
    - --Act III: Costumes, open meadow, sig. (Box B4, Folder 14)
    - --Act III.2: details, 29x19.5 cm., sig. (Box B4, Folder 15)
    - --Act III.2: platform elevation, 22x26 cm., sig. (Box B4, Folder 16)
    - --Property details, 28.5x19 cm., sig. (Box B4, Folder 17)
    - 2 technical drawings (Box 14-9-2, Folder 2)
    - Production notes, 15 p. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 17 photographs of sets and set drawings (Box 8, Folder 5)
      [See also Vienna, 1908, 1909-11]
  - La Gioconda, February 6, 1914
    Opera by Amilcare Ponchielli, libretto by Tobia Gorrio, after the play by Victor Hugo Angélo, tyran de Padoue, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Emmy Destinn as La Gioconda, Florencio Constantino as Enzo, Marguerite D'Alvarez as Laura and Mario Ancona as Barnaba.
    - Production notes, 6 p. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Ground plan (Box B4, Folder 18)
  - L'Amore dei Tre Re, February 9, 1914 (New)
    Opera in three acts by Italo Montemezzi, adapted from poem by Sem Benelli, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Edoardo Ferrari-Fontana as Avito, Lucrezia Bori as Fiora and Pasquale Amato as Manfredo.
    - Libretto (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 3 photographs of Met production (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1 page from Met program (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ground plan (Box B4, Folder 19)
    - Ground plan and elevation (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1 cast list (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 10 photographs of costumes, sets and set drawings (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Manon, March 18, 1914
    Opera by Jules Massenet, libretto by Henri Meilhac & Philippe Gille, after the novel by Antoine-Francois Prevost, L'histoire du chevalier de Grieux et de Manon Lescaut, conducted by Edouard Tournon with Jenny Dufau as Manon, Lucien Muratore as Des Grieux and Alban Grand as De Brétigny.
    - 3 p. from Met program (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 5 photographs of set (Box 8, Folder 8)
      [See also Metropolitan Opera December 22, 1928]
  - Otello, Paris Tour, May 5, 1914 (New)
    Opera by Giuseppe Verdi, libretto by Francesco Berio di Salsa, based on the play by William Shakespeare, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Edoardo Ferrari-Fontana as Otello, Vanni Marcoux as Iago and Nellie Melba as Desdemona.
    - Libretto (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Playbook (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
    - --Iago (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - --Act II: Garden (Box B4, Folder 20)
    - --Act III: Castle interior, sig. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - --Act III: Castle detail (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Article on Verdi, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 3 technical drawings (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 7 ground plans (Box 14-9-1, Folder A.8)
    - Production notes, 6 p. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 15 photographs of sets and set drawings (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Parsifal, Paris Tour, June 3, 1914 (New)
    Opera by Richard Wagner, conducted by Felix Weingartner with Johannes Sembach as Parsifal, Margarete Matzenauer as Kundry and August Kiess as Klingsor.
    - 2 librettos in German, pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 10)